Contact

david.lee.johnson@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dave-johnson-993754195 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Writing

Leadership

Machine Learning

Certifications

GIAC Certified Incident Handler (GCIH)

GIAC Certified Forensic Analyst (GCFA)

Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP)

Honors-Awards
2020 IT Innovator Award

Dave Johnson

Customer Success Manager @Feedly

Verona, Wisconsin, United States

Summary

As an FBI analyst, I've tracked botnets, briefed government officials, and collaborated with international partners to combat cyber crime. Over the past seven years, I performed incident response and built a successful cyber threat intelligence program. My most recent efforts have focused on applying machine learning techniques to solve problems in the security industry.

Skills: Python, Flask, JavaScript, PyTorch, Keras, Scikit-learn, and experience building deep learning models with several neural network architectures (CNNs, LSTMs, and GRUs)

Experience

Feedly

Senior CTI Customer Success Manager February 2023 - Present (1 year 2 months)

University of Minnesota

Adjunct Faculty - Cyber Threat Intelligence Instructor

September 2022 - September 2023 (1 year 1 month) Greater Minneapolis-St. Paul Area

RSM US LLP

6 years 6 months

Cyber Incident Response Manager

May 2022 - March 2023 (11 months)

Minneapolis, Minnesota, United States

Cyber Threat Intelligence Manager

April 2020 - May 2022 (2 years 2 months)

Minneapolis, Minnesota, United States

- Established an automated threat hunting process to dynamically retrieve indicators of compromise (IOCs) extracted from malware samples found in the wild

- Created a web application in React and Flask to summarize intelligence from news sources with the BERT transformer model
- Created a production application using natural language processing (NLP) to automatically identify and triage malicious emails reported by users
- Used machine learning algorithms to automatically identify patterns in malicious emails for improving security defenses
- Created a Q&A chatbot application to assist the IT Governance team respond to client questionnaires.

Senior Cyber Intelligence Researcher October 2016 - April 2020 (3 years 7 months)

- Created a novel web application with Node.js and MongoDB to facilitate cyber tabletop exercises
- Established a successful cyber intelligence program based on all steps of the intelligence cycle
- Used computer skills to automate intelligence collection and data processing
- Created finished intelligence on a weekly, monthly, and annual basis

Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)
Intelligence Analyst
July 2009 - October 2016 (7 years 4 months)
Milwaukee

- Conducted intelligence analysis to support a variety of cyber criminal investigations
- Participated in botnet takedown efforts to stem global cyber crime
- Briefed foreign government officials on national security issues

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Science - BS, Psychology and Legal Studies · (2004 - 2009)

National Intelligence University

Master's degree, Science and Technology Intelligence · (2014 - 2016)

Udacity

Nanodegree, Deep Learning · (2019 - 2020)